

Asma Rauf

Phone: 310-529-7630 Location: Anaheim, CA 92807 Email: asma.rasool@gmail.com



LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/asma-rauf/

Trailhead: https://trailhead.salesforce.com/en/me/00550000006h1FLAAY

Summary

I am a certified salesforce developer and administrator with 8+ years of experience in IT industry. I enjoy understanding business processes and implementing technology effectively to solve problems. I am a team player & I feel motivated by working in a collaborative environment.

Education

Bachelors in Computer Science (University of Punjab)

Certifications

- Salesforce Certified Administrator (ADM201)
- Salesforce Certified Platform Developer I (DEV401)

Tools & Technologies

- Salesforce development: Apex, Visualforce, Lightning Components, SOSL, SOQL
- CRM: Salesforce.com
- Programming languages: C, C++, JAVA, Groovy
- Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, XML, Eclipse
- Databases: MySQL, Oracle, MS Access
- CI, Build, Source Control tools: Visual Studio Code, SVN, GitHub, VSS, Workbench, Data Migration Tool
- Bug tracking: Jira, Test Director, TestTrack Pro, Bugzilla

Work Experience

| Episource LLC | Salesforce Admin/Developer | Jan 2018 to Date |
|---------------|----------------------------|------------------|
| | | |

Episource provides healthcare analytics and business technology solutions to Health Insurance companies in the US. I am working as a salesforce administrator and developer to manage their Salesforce enterprise edition org. In my role, I have

- Defined Workflow rules, Processes to automate business scenarios and save time
- Created customized Visualforce pages to meet business needs using standard and custom controllers and data tables
- Created tools to update records in bulk using batch Apex and Custom list Settings
- Enhanced test coverage by writing test classes for uncovered and enhanced code
- Customized various standard objects, page layouts and defined custom objects, fields, related lists, roll up summary fields, formula fields, record types, list views to meet requirements

- Managed and configured various installed packages such as field service lightning, Pardot, Conga Composer,
 Actiongrid and ZenKraft Shipmate for USPS
- Written scripts to clean up data to improve accuracy in reports.

| Sneha Karma Foundation | Salesforce Admin/Developer (Volunteer) | July 2017 to Jan |
|------------------------|--|------------------|
| | | 2018 |

Sneha Karma Foundation is a nonprofit working to educate girls in rural parts of India and eliminate poverty. I worked as Salesforce Administrator and Developer to manage their Enterprise Nonprofit Success Pack (NPSP). I have

- Customized Salesforce.com to match the functional needs of the organization
- Customized various standard objects, page layouts and defined custom objects, fields, related lists, roll up summary fields to meet requirements
- Automated business processes (email alerts and tasks) through workflow rules and process builder
- Customized Salesforce1 Mobile app through Compact layouts and object-specific quick actions
- Created Apex triggers to automatically update Household accounts whenever donated amount exceeds expectation
- Created Visualforce pages using Standard & Custom controllers in developer sandbox
- Performed thorough testing in partial copy sandbox before creating outbound change sets.
- Performed Data cleaning before importing records through Data Import Wizards
- Created a Feedback form using Lightening Components to gather volunteer feedback
- Implemented role hierarchies, sharing rules and security settings
- Created Reports (tabular, summary, matrix) and dashboards to analyze monthly and quarterly progress
- Provided support and training to assist end users in creating reports, dashboards and utilizing salesforce features to increase productivity

| Evollve Inc. (Ozobot) | QA Analyst | Oct 2018 to Dec 2018 |
|-----------------------|------------|----------------------|
| | | |

Evollve Inc. makes toy robots to teach kids programming. I worked as a QA Analyst to test their mobile App and web programming tool.

- Automated scenarios to test their website.
- Automated test cases using selenium framework in Java to test the web programming tool
- Tested programming the bot with their mobile App

| EdocSynergy | Lead BA & QA | Apr 2009 to Sep 2014 |
|-------------|--------------|----------------------|
|-------------|--------------|----------------------|

EdocSynergy was a startup and I worked as a QA Lead and Business Analyst on the development of an EMR System.

- Gathered requirements from onsite and communicated to development team.
- Analyzed customer requirements and resolved issues, discrepancies prior to development kick-off enormously saving team effort in later phases of development.
- Created and maintained all project related documentation such as Requirement & Functional Specification
 Documents, Field Mappings, Test Cases and Testing Status Reports for effective communication between team
 members.
- Automated test cases using selenium framework in **Java** to test the web application and portals which significantly reduced unit and load testing time.

- Created test scripts using Sikuli framework in Java to find web elements and reduce coding time.
- Created test scripts in Groovy for SoapUI to test SOAP and REST APIs

| Systems Limited | Senior QA Analyst | Jul 2007 to Feb 2009 |
|-----------------|-------------------|----------------------|
| | | |

I worked as a Senior QA Analyst to test the web-based ERP & Supply Chain BI System. The project was a technology upgrade from VB to .Net for the ERP desktop application.

- Supervised testing team activities from time to time and provided time estimations for QA team activities such as test planning, test data generation and test execution.
- Reviewed Functional Requirements for Test Planning, reported and got issues resolved using web-based Issue Management System (JIRA).
- Identified and documented test scenarios in Mercury Test Director based on functional document and domain knowledge.
- Created test scripts in Java using selenium framework to test Sales and purchase orders
- Performed localized regression and integration testing and identified major ripples in application.
- Tested Enterprise Data Warehouse and BI Reports using Oracle with TOAD and MS SQL Server. ☐ Effectively trained and mentored new resources in business domain and QA practices.

| Strategic Systems International | QA Analyst | Mar 2006 to Jul 2007 |
|---------------------------------|------------|----------------------|
| | | |

I worked as a QA analyst to test a desktop-based application at SSI which was a startup. The application was used to speed up decision making in dynamic financial markets.

- Generated detailed Test cases using TestTrack Pro despite the lack of extensive project documentation available to define user specifications that helped catching intensive application issues.
- Effectively interacted with client to share analysis, design and testing status reports.

References

Available on request